Anne Burlak Timpson Papers, 1886-2003 (bulk 1912-2003)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS 1932-2004, 2.25 linear ft.
  This series provides an overview of Anne Burlak Timpson's personal and political life. The subseries Biographical information documents Timpson's life through short biographical statements, plays and poetry written about her, oral histories and interviews, as well as newspaper clippings and articles that document many of Timpson's arrests and indictments. The F.B.I. files on Timpson document both the close surveillance the government had on her as well as indicate people that Timpson met with, meetings she attended, as well as the government's case against her under the Smith Act. Additional newspaper clippings about Timpson and the Smith Act is located in SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS. There are transcripts for some of the taped oral histories and interviews. The Family subseries includes information about Timpson's husband, siblings, and son. The subseries, Daily calendars, contains newspaper clippings and other notes that were found with the calendars. This series also contains information about awards given to Timpson, tributes made before and after her death, and buttons and other memorabilia documenting the organizations to which she was dedicated. There are also some files on Timpson's vacations. Additional information about trips that Timpson took is in SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS AND SLIDES and SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS.
  [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1937-2002, 2.25 linear ft.
  This series is organized into two subseries: Family and Friends and associates. There is extensive correspondence between Timpson and her husband in the late 1930s and early 1940s, as well as letters written to Timpson by her brothers from Russia and the Ukraine from the 1960s through the 1990s. Correspondence with her brothers includes not only family news but also reactions to political and social events in the United States and the Soviet Union. The subseries Friends and associates reveals Timpson's commitment to her causes, the affection she held for aging comrades, and her willingness to share the story of her life with others. It is arranged in alphabetical order by first letter of the last name; more prolific correspondents have their own folder. The bulk of the subseries is from the 1980s and 1990s. Although most of the correspondence is to Anne Burlak Timpson, she began keeping typed copies of many of her letters in the 1990s, and they are interfiled with the correspondence she received from others.
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES 1928-95, 2 linear ft.
  This series contains notes, drafts, and completed and uncompleted manuscripts by Anne Burlak Timpson. There are four subseries, the first of which, Published writings, includes articles, letters to the editor, and newsletters that Timpson edited. The subseries Unpublished writings includes a few diaries, but the majority of the subseries consists of materials related to her incomplete autobiography. Correspondence relating to the autobiography is located in this subseries, arranged chronologically. Primary documents relating to subjects covered in her autobiography are in this series as well as in SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES and SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES. Some of the microfilmed copies of newspaper clippings are in poor shape and are probably too faded for photocopying. Most of the Speeches subseries contains notes for speeches rather than complete works. The subseries Tributes includes notes, programs, and occasionally texts of testimonials and eulogies Timpson gave for friends and colleagues.
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES 1928-98, 4.25 linear ft.
  Files in this series are arranged alphabetically and include organizations in which Timpson was heavily involved, like the Communist Party of the USA, and groups to which she gave money, like the United Seniors Association. The series includes notes, minutes, reports, newspaper clippings, newsletters, correspondence, brochures, and other printed materials. The largest groups of files relate to the U.S. Council for International Friendship and the Communist Party of the USA. Documents in both files reveal the operations of the organization at the local, state, and national levels. Files on the Communist Party newspapers are not the newspapers themselves but materials related to the running of the newspaper, such as fundraising. Articles or letters to the editor of Communist newspapers are located in SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES. Information on Communist Party candidates is in SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES. Organizations with very limited amounts of materials have been moved to the appropriate locations in SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES.
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES 1886-98, 5.75 linear ft.
  The subject files are arranged alphabetically and contain information on individuals, legislation, categories of people (such as women or youth), and geographic regions. Additional subject files relevant to Timpson's autobiography are located in SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES. The bulk of the subject files are from a U.S. perspective, although there are some international materials in the subject files (such as labor and communism). There are also files on specific countries, most of them listed under their names, with the exception of some materials located under the heading Latin America and the Caribbean. Most of the state-level political candidates are from Massachusetts, but there are a few from outside of the state. Topics that are well-covered include elections, labor, legislation, nuclear weapons, peace, politics, and the Soviet Union. Documents relating to Timpson's indictments under the Smith and McCarran Acts are located in this series under the name of the legislation. There are also songs and poetry related to a wide variety of topics in this series.
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS AND SLIDES 1912-98, 1.25 linear ft.
  The bulk of this series documents Timpson's personal life, beginning in her infancy and ending a few years before her death. There are, however, political images as well, including several photographs of Timpson with raised fists during protests and with friends and associates. The Photographs subseries includes her trips to Cuba, Yugoslavia, Spain, and the Soviet Union. Other photographs, especially of Timpson and her family, are located in SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS. The subseries Slides mostly contains family images, but it also includes commercially generated images of Leningrad.
- SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS 1933-97, 3.5 linear ft.
  This series includes sketches, photographs, commentary, maps, newspaper clippings and other memorabilia. Most of the material in this series documents family life and the relationships among the family members of the Burlak and Timpson families. Two albums document the 1933 Naumkeag Steam Cotton Company strike. Two albums document her trials under Smith Act indictment, and seven albums provide vivid details of husband Arthur's World War II battles. The World War II scrapbooks appear to have been based upon notes written during the summer of 1945 while Arthur was waiting to come home and cover the period between 1943 and 1945. The scrapbooks themselves were created much later, probably in the late 1950s or early 1960s. Due to the fragile nature of the scrapbooks, many of the albums have been reformatted to preserve their content. Although the original text of most of the scrapbooks was not preserved, those texts that included initials indicating which family member wrote which piece of the narrative have been kept.
- SERIES VIII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS 1961-2003, 1.5 linear ft.
  This bulk of this series relates to Anne Burlak Timpson's family and her oral histories and interviews. The subseries Audiocassettes, VHS cassettes, and Mini DV cassettes all have preservation masters and use copies. They are arranged by type of the original material. If the use copy is in a different format, the format will be indicated in brackets after the title. The reels in the subseries Super 8 need to be reformatted before they can be viewed. Please check with the Sophia Smith Collection several weeks in advance if you are interested in viewing the films in this subseries.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS 1932-2004
  - Contents (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Short biographies, 1932-95, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles and newspaper clippings, 1931-97, [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES, SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Plays and poetry, 1981-83, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Interviews and oral histories, 1981-97, [see also SERIES VIII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS] (Box 1, Folder 5-10)
  - Family
    - General, 1959-89, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - John and Anna Burlak, 1982-90, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Nicholas Burlak (Michael Nichols), 1966-91 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Arthur Timpson, 1937-45, 1975-85, undated, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Abraham Lincoln Brigade, SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES-Spanish Civil War] (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - William (Bill) Timpson, 1979-96, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Awards, 1982-97, undated, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Wonder Woman Foundation, Rhode Island Labor History Society] (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Tributes, 1983-2004, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - F.B.I. file on Anne Burlak Timpson, 1940-88 (Box 1a-1b)
  - Education: Books from the Lenin School, 1933-36 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Passports, 1935-85 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Trips
    - Russia, 1981, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Yugoslavia, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Veterans of Abraham Lincoln Brigade 50th Anniversary Trip to Spain, 1984-86 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Other trips, 1979-91, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Financial information, 1964-66, 1982-85 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Daily calendars
    - 1968-89 (Box 2, Folder 10-15)
    - 1991-94 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Address book, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia: buttons and mini-banners, 1975-94, undated (Box 3, Folder 4-16)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1937-2002
  - Family
    - Burlak (Box 3)
      - Anna and John, 1944-98, undated (Box 4)
      - Mike, 1961-95, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-8)
      - Nicholas (Box 5)
        - 1957-89 (Box 5, Folder 9-14)
        - 1990-96, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
      - Valerie (Lera), 1964-96 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Chrusniak, Evelyn (Evie) Timpson, 1991-96 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Timpson
      - Arthur, circa 1937-43 (Box 6, Folder 6-11)
      - Kellee, 1994-98 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - William (Bill) and Marlene, 1968-98, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Wright, David and Kathryn (Kat) Timpson, 1964-96, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Other family, 1955-98 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Birthday cards to Kathryn Timpson, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Third party family correspondence, 1943-95, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Friends and associates
    - A, 1984-96 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Amery, Al and Priscilla, 1982-92 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - B, 1957-94 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Buhle, Paul, 1978-90, undated, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Interviews and oral histories, SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES-Autobiography, and OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - C, 1977-95 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - D, 1969-95 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - F, 1963-94, n. d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Figuereido, Eula, [see Matusiak, Eulalia (Eula) Figueiredo Pappandreu]
    - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1964, undated, [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES-Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, McCarran Act, Smith Act] (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Folsom, Franklin and Mary, 1988-90 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - G, 1955-88, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - H, 1977-99, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Herzog, Anne, 1993-95 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - J, 1968-90, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Andy and Hannah, 1987-93 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - K, 1961-97, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Kerry, John, 1985-96, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - L, 1980-91 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - M, 1983-93, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Matusiak, Eulalia (Eula) Figueiredo Papaandreu, 1956-2002, n.d., [see also SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS] (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
    - Moakley, Joseph, 1982-96, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Molloy, Scott, [see SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES-Autobiography]
    - N, 1986-96 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Obler, Charlie, 1987-97, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - P, 1962-94 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Papaandreu, Eulalia (Eula), [see Matusiak, Eulalia (Eula) Figueiredo Papaandreu] (Box 7)
    - Payne, Roz, 1984-92, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - R, 1980-97 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - S, 1963-97, undated, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS (Don Searle to ABT)] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - T, 1977-96 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - V, 1982-83 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Vlasikin, Tanya and Vasiliy (Vasya), 1978-90, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Voichick, Jennifer, [see SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES--Autobiography]
    - W, 1985-95, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Whitehead, Fred, 1982-93 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Winston, Henry (Winnie), 1971-83 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Winter, Carl and Helen, 1988-98 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Z, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified, 1978-94, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Messages from groups, 1976-91, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Students from Asian American Civic Association, Inc., 1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Death of Arthur Timpson, 1976-82, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Get-well cards, 1990-98, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Third party correspondence, 1969-95, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES 1928-95
  - Published writings (Box 8)
    - Articles, 1971-95, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Letters to the editor, 1982-89, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Newsletters edited
      - Spotlight on New England, 1944-45 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Roxbury Voice, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Unpublished writings
    - Diaries, 1981-87 (Box 9, Folder 7-9)
    - Autobiography
      - Contacts, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1977-87, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Expenses, 1982-86 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Research notes, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
        - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - 1929 arrests, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - Atlanta 6 (1930), 1930, 1978-83, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - Communist Party, 1932-55, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Family history, 1982-85, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - J.P. Stevens, 1975-83, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
        - Reagan era, 1982-85, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Strikes, 1929-88, undated (Box 10, Folder 2-6)
        - Textile unions, 1928-32, 1955-86, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - Unemployed councils, 1932, 1980, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
        - Unemployment insurance, 1934-35, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Rough draft (incomplete), undated, [note: please use preservation copy instead of original] (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - Responses to others' writings, 1982-88 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Notes, 1976-94, undated (Box 11, Folder 1-7)
  - Speeches, 1937, 1975-94, undated (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
  - Tributes
    - General, 1978-93, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Otis Hood, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Don Batchelder, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES 1928-98
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1938, 1972-97, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS-Family-- Arthur Timpson, Trip to Spain, SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES-Spanish Civil War, SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS] (Box 12, Folder 11-13)
  - Alan Thomson Defense Fund, 1989-92, undated, [see also U.S. Council for International Friendship] (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - AFL-CIO, 1945-97, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Boston/Kiev Sister City Association, Inc., 1982-88, undated, [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Peace] (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Boston Peace Council, 1981-86, undated, [see also U.S. Peace Council] (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Center for Marxist Education, 1979-92, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Citizens for Participation in Political Action (CPPAX), 1975-97, undated, [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES-- Civil Rights, Racism] (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Committee of Correspondence, 1991-96, undated, [see also Communist Party of the United States of America] (Box 13, Folder 3-7)
  - Communist Party of the United States of America, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES-Autobiography-Research notes; and OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 13)
    - General
      - 1961-91 (Box 13, Folder 8-11)
      - 1992-98 (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    - Communist Party of New England, 1940-85, undated (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Massachusetts State Committee/District, 1937-96, undated, [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Elections] (Box 14, Folder 9-10)
    - Other districts, 1988-94, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Club, 1966-95, undated (Box 14, Folder 12-15)
    - Articles and notes, 1954, 1981-97, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Contact information, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Newspapers
      - Daily World, 1973-85, undated (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
      - People's Daily World, 1985-90, undated (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
      - People's Weekly World, 1990-97, undated (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
    - People, 1961-96, undated (Box 15, Folder 9-11)
    - Publications, [see Appendix for title list]
      - A-C (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
      - D-Z (Box 16-17)
    - Recruitment, 1985-97, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Seventy-fifth anniversary, 1994-95 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Young Communist League, 1937-38, 1983-97, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Community Church of Boston, 1960-97 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Davis-Putter Scholarship Fund, 1974-97, undated, [see also SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS] (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Fourth United Nations World Conference on Women, 1995-96, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Frederick Douglass Bookstore, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC), [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Civil liberties]
    - General, 1947-65 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Investigation of Communist Activities in the New England Area, 1958, [Spine title: New England 1951-57] (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - International Peace Walk, 1987-88, undated, [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Peace] (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - International Physicians for Prevention of Nuclear War, 1985-92 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Jobs with Peace, 1980-89, undated (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
  - Little Flags Theatre, 1976-91 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Massachusetts Committee for the Bill of Rights, 1954-55, undated, [see also HUAC, SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES-- Civil liberties, Smith Act] (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Massachusetts Special Commission on Communism, 1938-59, [see also CPUSA] (Box 19, Folder 7-10)
  - Memorial Committee for Klarfield and Zeidman, 1975-76 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Mobilization for Survival, 1983-94, undated, [see also CPPAX, SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Peace] (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, 1975-96, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - National Council of American Soviet Friendship, [see U.S. Council for International Friendship] (Box 19)
  - National Textile Workers Union, 1928-34, 1990, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Interviews and oral histories, SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES] (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Peace Child, 1985-87, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Peace Fleece, 1985-86, undated, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Promoting Enduring Peace, 1984-95, undated (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
  - Rainbow Coalition, 1987-97, [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Racism, Mel King] (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Rhode Island Labor History Society, 1977-97, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Samantha Smith Foundation, 1983-88, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Seeds of Change, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Soviet Peace Committee, 1981-86 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Ukrainian American League, 1980-89, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - United Senior Association, 1995, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Council for International Friendship, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
    - General, 1942-46 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Boston Committee, 1971-91, undated (Box 20, Folder 13-19)
    - Other branches, 1981-91, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Bylaws and resolutions, 1979, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Exchange trips and goodwill missions, 1988-93 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Executive Committee, 1983-97, undated (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
    - Fact sheets, 1982-85 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters, 1982-91 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Peace Council, 1979-93, undated, [see also Boston Peace Council; and OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Wonder Woman Foundation, 1981-84, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Awards; and [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS]] (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Young Workers Liberation League, 1979-86, undated, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 21, Folder 10)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES 1886-98
  - Afghanistan, 1980-94 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1943, 1981-95 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Atlanta 6, 1930, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Appalachia, 1972-91, undated, [see also Don West] (Box 21, Folder 14-15)
  - Berkman, Edith, 1931-32, [see also Strikes] (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Black liberation, 1932-85, undated, [see also Civil rights, Racism] (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Bonner-Lyons, Pat, 1971-73, undated, [see also Boston, Education, SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Memorabilia] (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Boston, 1954, 1980-94, undated, [See also SERIES VII. SCRAPBOOKS] (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Caldicott, Helen, 1977-83, undated, [see also Peace, Nuclear weapons] (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Chernobyl, 1986-91, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Civil liberties, 1942-94, undated, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-CPPAX, HUAC] (Box 22, Folder 7-9)
  - Civil rights, 1963-97, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Clinton, Bill, 1992-94, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Communism: International, 1957-96, undated, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES-Unpublished-Autobiography; SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--CPUSA] (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Cuba, 1963-97, undated (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Curtis, Mark, 1989-92, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Angela, 1972-84, undated, [see also Elections, SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Memorabilia] (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Death penalty, 1989-94, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Dotterman, Gary, 1987-95, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Du Bois, W. E. B., 1987-94 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Education, 1937, 1975-95, undated, [see also Pat Bonner-Lyons, Elections, Racism, Unions] (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - El Salvador, 1982-90, [see also Latin America and the Caribbean] (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
  - Elections, [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-CPPAX] (Box 23)
    - President, 1972-96, undated (Box 23, Folder 11-13)
    - Congress, 1933-98, undated (Box 23, Folder 14-15)
    - State elections/issues, 1970-97, undated, [see also H. Stewart Hughes, Florence Luscomb] (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
    - Massachusetts-General, 1938-97, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Boston, 1965-95, undated, [see also Pat Bonner-Lyons, Gary Dotterman, Mel King, Ed Teixeira] (Box 24, Folder 5-9)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1969-95, undated, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Gays in the military, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Guinier, Ewart, 1969-90, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Guns and violence, 1984-94, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Haiti, 1993-94, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Hall, Gus, 1970-93, [see alsoElections,SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--CPUSA] (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Harrison, William H., 1968-89, undated, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES-Newsletters edited-- Roxbury Voice] (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Health care, 1975-97, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Hood, Frances and Otis, 1954-94, undated, [see alsoSmith Act,SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES--Tributes] (Box 24, Folder 18)